On the Beach is a drama, science fiction, tv movie
film directed by Russell Mulcahy.
The world has finally managed to blow itself up and only Australia has been spared from
nuclear destruction and a gigantic wave of radiation is floating in on the breezes.
One American sub located in the Pacific has survived and
is met with disdain by the Australians.
The calculations of Australia's most renowned
scientist says the country is doomed.
However, one of his rivals says that he is wrong.
He believes that a 1000 people can be relocated to the northern hemisphere,
where his assumptions indicate the radiation levels may be lower.
The American Captain is asked to take a mission to the
north to determine which scientist is right.
Cmdr. Dwight Towers, played by Armand Assante.
Moira Davidson, played by Rachel Ward.
Dr. Julian Osborne, played by Bryan Brown.
Mary Davidson Holmes, played by Jacqueline McKenzie.
Lt. Peter Holmes, played by Grant Bowler.
Jenny Holmes, played by Tieghan Webber.
On the Beach is a 2000 apocalyptic drama television film directed by Russell
Mulcahy and starring Armand Assante, Bryan Brown, and Rachel Ward.
In America, it aired on Showtime on 28 May 2000 and
in Australia it aired on Channel 7.
The film is a remake of a 1959 film, which was also based on the 1957 novel by Nevil Shute, but updates the setting of the story to the
film's then-future of 2006, starting with placing the crew on a fictional Los Angeles-class submarine, USS Charleston (SSN-704).
The film explores themes of australia, based on novel or
book, submarine, atomic bomb, dystopia.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.